Sourav Saha

Personal Information Kolkata, India souravsaha1605@gmail.com

8981782777 - LinkedIn - Kaggle

Career Summary 5.6 years of professional work experience on **Data Science and Data Structure**. Relevant work experience on Sales forecasting, Named Entity Recognition, Tag Extraction, Classification, non personalized Recommendation using graph theory. Mentored more than 50 interns in different domains for my hobby initiative.

SKILLS

Python, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Deep Learning, Networkx, Seaborn, PySpark, GCP, Azure

Professional EXPERIENCE

Mindtree - Senior Software Engineer

July 2021 - Present

- Retail: Identify promotions and distribution efficiency after baseline sales prediction.
- Healthcare: Budget forecasting for different modalities (products) across different areas.

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd. - System Engineer (TCS Digital)

January 2017 - June 2021

- Insurance: Filed PATENT on Unemployment fraud detection for a Govt. state.
- Healthcare: Implemented Named Entity Recognition using LSTM algorithm with Tensorflow
- Retail: **Inventory management** across stores and product.
- Recommendation problems using NetworkX and experience working in Grakn graph database.
- Tag Extraction using POS from front-end using JavaScript
- Datasets preparation and implementation of classification and document similarity problems
- Aspect based sentiment analysis.

FusionCharts Technologies Pvt. Ltd., - JS Developer Trainee

July 2016 - December 2016

• Adding new functionalities to different type of charts and creating new charts based on company requirements. Implementations were made using maths, data structure with JavaScript.

Hobby Projects • Machine Learning Hackathons

- Predict Hospital stay duration for COVID patients using CatBoost, Deep Learning Rank: 142 / 19Kc
- Predict Future Sales using XGBRegressor Rank: 277 / 8K &
- Twitter Sentiment Analysis using LSTM Rank: 416 / 15K
- BigMart Sales Prediction using StackingCVRegressor Rank: 1726 / 32K
- Time Series Forecasting of JetRail passengers using Prophet, Holt's Winter, Sarimax Rank: 399 / 19KC
- Exam Preparation Online An online portal to simplify the email digest for daily learning activities on machine learning, sports and technology. It also features interview experiences and success stories in simplified format.
 - Filter out blog links from mail contents and broadcast relevant contents via website and chrome extension.
 - Extract text using tesseract from Images of question papers and segregate them to individual questions
 - 200+ Subscribers, 300+ monthly visits, 2K unique visits before interviews, 1.3K FB likes
- Google Search Recommendation 2 Chrome extension to track online activity of user. Visual representation of online activity through charts and recommended links in Google search page based on their past activities.

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning

- Supply Chain for Management Consultants and Business Analysts Udemy 2
- RA: Data Science and Supply Chain analytics. A-Z with Python Udemy &
- Natural Language Processing in TensorFlow Coursera
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning Coursera
- TCS Machine Learning E2 competency ♂
- Basic Sentiment Analysis with TensorFlow Coursera ♂
- Data Engineering, Big Data, and Machine Learning on GCP Specialization Coursera & &
- MLOps (Machine Learning Operations) Fundamentals Coursera
- DP-100: A-Z Machine Learning using Azure Machine Learning Udemytz
- Data Analysis Using Pyspark Coursera 🗷
- Exploratory Data Analysis with Seaborn Coursera
- Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach by University of Washington Coursera &

EDUCATION

Bits Pilani, Executive M.Tech. Data Science. 2021 - 2023

Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata, B.Tech., (DGPA): 8.43 / 10

Nava Nalanda High School, Kolkata, Higher Secondary: 68

Nava Nalanda High School, Kolkata, Secondary: 80.3